<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Publications | ]]></title>
  <link href="/news/categories/publications/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="/"/>
  <updated>2017-10-20T23:58:48+02:00</updated>
  <id>/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[SARL Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accepted papers at PAAMS and SARL]]></title>
    <link href="/news/2017/03/13/accepted-papers-at-paams-and-sarl.html"/>
    <updated>2017-03-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>/news/2017/03/13/accepted-papers-at-paams-and-sarl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two papers about SARL are accepted, the first at the <a href="http://www.paams.net/">PAAMS-17</a> international conference, and the second at the <a href="http://www.multiagent.fr/Conferences:SARL17">SARL-17</a> international workshop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best paper award at CHARMS2015]]></title>
    <link href="/news/2015/08/24/paper-at-harms2015.html"/>
    <updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>/news/2015/08/24/paper-at-harms2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An article using SARL has been awarded at the 2015 <a href="http://web.ics.purdue.edu/%7Eematson/CHARMS.html">International Workshop on Communication for Humans, Agents, Robots, Machines and Sensors</a>, 17-20 August 2015 / Belfort, France.</p>

<p><strong>Paper description</strong>
<strong>A New Perspective on Multi-Agent Environment with SARL</strong></p>

<p><strong>Abstract:</strong>
The environment is now considered as a first class abstraction in multiagent systems. However, the boundary between real and
simulated environment and the application logic is not so well defined. Depending on applications, the environment as a space
shared between agents may integrate physical, communication or social dimensions where agents interact. In this paper, authors
introduce an agent environment model supporting the intrasic distributed and hierarchical natures of the environment. It is defined
using the fundamental concepts provided by metamodel related to the SARL programming language.</p>

<p><strong>Citing Details</strong></p>

<p><ol class="bibliography"><li><span id="harms2015">Rodriguez, S., Galland, S., &amp; Gaud, N. (2015). A New Perspective on Multi-Agent Environment with SARL. In <i>International Workshop on Communication for Humans, Agents, Robots, Machines and Sensors</i> (pp. 526–531). Belfort, France: Elsevier. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.procs.2015.07.246</span>

<div id="harms2015-materials">
	<ul class="nav nav-pills">
		
		<li> <a data-toggle="collapse" href="#harms2015-abstract"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-eye-open"></span> Abstract</a></li>
		

		<li><a data-toggle="collapse" href="#harms2015-bibtex"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-bullhorn"></span> BibTeX</a></li>

		

		
		<li><a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1877050915017275"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-log-out"> Download</a></li>
		

		

	</ul>

	
	<pre id="harms2015-abstract" class="pre pre-scrollable collapse">The environment is now considered as a first class abstraction in multiagent systems. However, the boundary between real and simulated environment and the application logic is not so well defined. Depending on applications, the environment as a space shared between agents may integrate physical, communication or social dimensions where agents interact. In this paper, authors introduce a new view for structuring the notion of environment in a multiagent systems using the fundamental concepts provided by the SARL programming language.</pre>
	

	<pre id="harms2015-bibtex" class="pre pre-scrollable collapse">@inproceedings{harms2015,
  address = {Belfort, France},
  booktitle = {International Workshop on Communication for Humans, Agents, Robots, Machines and Sensors},
  doi = {10.1016/j.procs.2015.07.246},
  issn = {1877-0509},
  keywords = {Multiagent systems, Environment, Interaction, Programming language},
  month = aug,
  note = {Best Paper Award},
  organization = {Procedia Computer Science},
  pages = {526--531},
  publisher = {Elsevier},
  link = {{http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1877050915017275}},
  year = {2015},
  title = {A New Perspective on Multi-Agent Environment with {SARL}},
  author = {Rodriguez, Sebastian and Galland, St{\'e}phane and Gaud, Nicolas}
}
</pre>

</div>
</li></ol></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accepted paper with SARL at PAAMS15]]></title>
    <link href="/news/2015/04/24/accepted-paper-with-sarl-at-paams15.html"/>
    <updated>2015-04-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>/news/2015/04/24/accepted-paper-with-sarl-at-paams15</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An article using SARL has been accepted at the 2015 <a href="http://www.paams.net/">International Conference on Practical Applications of Agents and Multi-Agent Systems (PAAMS)</a>, 3rd-5th June 2015 / Salamanca, Spain.</p>

<p><strong>Paper description</strong>
<strong>Contextualize Agent Interactions by Combining Communication and Physical Dimensions in the Environment</strong></p>

<p><strong>Abstract:</strong>
The environment, as a space shared between agents, is a key component of multiagent systems (MAS). Depending on systems, this space may integrate physical, communication or communication dimensions.
Each of them has its own process and rules to support agents&#39; interaction.
The dimensions of the environment are generally connected either outside of the agents or within each agent, according to the target application.
In order to ensure a multiagent control, the relations between dimensions must be explicit outside of the agents.
Using these relations between the environment dimensions, the interaction becomes also multi-dimensional.
In this paper, rules and mechanisms to make this connection outside of the agents are formalized.
The model connects the physical and communication dimensions to realize contextualized interactions. It is implemented using the SARL multiagent programming language, and illustrated with an urban traffic simulation.</p>

<p><strong>Citing Details</strong></p>

<p><ol class="bibliography"><li><span id="paams2015">Galland, S., Balbo, F., Gaud, N., Rodriguez, S., Picard, G., &amp; Boissier, O. (2015). Contextualize Agent Interactions by Combining Social and Physical Dimensions in the Environment. In Y. Demazeau &amp; K. Decker (Eds.), <i>13th International Conference on Practical Applications of Agents and Multi-Agent Systems (PAAMS)</i>.</span>

<div id="paams2015-materials">
	<ul class="nav nav-pills">
		
		<li> <a data-toggle="collapse" href="#paams2015-abstract"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-eye-open"></span> Abstract</a></li>
		

		<li><a data-toggle="collapse" href="#paams2015-bibtex"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-bullhorn"></span> BibTeX</a></li>

		

		

		
		<li><a href="http://www.multiagent.fr/extensions/ICAPManager/pdf/GallandBalboGaudRodriguezPicardBoissier2015_1.pdf"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-log-out"> Download PDF</a></li>
		

	</ul>

	
	<pre id="paams2015-abstract" class="pre pre-scrollable collapse">The environment, as a space shared between agents, is a key component of multiagent systems (MAS). Depending on systems, this space may integrate physical, communication or social dimensions. Each of them has its own process and rules to support agents’ interaction. The dimensions of the environment are generally connected either outside of the agents or within each agent, according to the target application. In order to ensure a multiagent control, the relations between dimensions must be explicit outside of the agents. Using these relations between the environment dimensions, the interaction becomes also multi-dimensional. In this paper, rules and mechanisms to make this connection outside of the agents are formalized. The model connects the physical and social dimensions to realize contextualized interactions. It is implemented using the SARL multiagent programming language, and illustrated with an urban traffic simulation.</pre>
	

	<pre id="paams2015-bibtex" class="pre pre-scrollable collapse">@inproceedings{paams2015,
  booktitle = {13th International Conference on Practical Applications of Agents and Multi-Agent Systems (PAAMS)},
  editor = {Demazeau, Yves and Decker, Keith},
  keywords = {Environment modeling; Simulation; Programming languages for agents and multi-agent systems; Smart cities},
  language = {english},
  month = jun,
  year = {2015},
  title = {Contextualize Agent Interactions by Combining Social and Physical Dimensions in the Environment},
  author = {Galland, St{\'e}phane and Balbo, Flavien and Gaud, Nicolas and Rodriguez, Sebastian and Picard, Gauthier and Boissier, Olivier},
  pdf = {{http://www.multiagent.fr/extensions/ICAPManager/pdf/GallandBalboGaudRodriguezPicardBoissier2015_1.pdf}}
}
</pre>

</div>
</li></ol></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accepted paper with SARL at AAMAS15]]></title>
    <link href="/news/2015/04/24/accepted-paper-with-sarl-at-aamas15.html"/>
    <updated>2015-04-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>/news/2015/04/24/accepted-paper-with-sarl-at-aamas15</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An article using SARL has been accepted at the 2015 <a href="http://www.aamas2015.com/en/">International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS)</a>, 4-5 May 2015 / Istanbul, Turkey.</p>

<p><strong>Paper description</strong>
<strong>A Multidimensional Environment Implementation for Enhancing Agent Interaction</strong></p>

<p><strong>Abstract:</strong>
The environment, as a space shared between agents, is a key component of multiagent systems (MAS).
Depending on systems, this space may integrate physical, communication or social dimensions.
Each of them has its own process and rules to support agents&#39; interaction. For instance, in the physical dimension, the rules may be based on the agents&#39; location.
The agents&#39; interaction is then contextualized, and the environment allows a multiagent control since it performs the interactions according to the state and rules of the MAS.
The dimensions of the environment are generally connected either in an application-dependent ad-hoc way outside of the agents or within each agent.
In order to ensure a multiagent control, the relations between dimensions must be explicit outside of the agents.
Using these relations between the environment dimensions, the interaction becomes also multidimensional.
In this paper, we propose to formalize rules and mechanisms to make this connection outside of the agents and in a generic way.</p>

<p><strong>Citing Details</strong></p>

<p><ol class="bibliography"><li><span id="aamas2015">Galland, S., Balbo, F., Gaud, N., Rodriguez, S., Picard, G., &amp; Boissier, O. (2015). A multidimensional environment implementation for enhancing agent interaction. In R. Bordini &amp; E. Elkind (Eds.), <i>Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS15)</i>. Istanbul, Turkey.</span>

<div id="aamas2015-materials">
	<ul class="nav nav-pills">
		
		<li> <a data-toggle="collapse" href="#aamas2015-abstract"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-eye-open"></span> Abstract</a></li>
		

		<li><a data-toggle="collapse" href="#aamas2015-bibtex"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-bullhorn"></span> BibTeX</a></li>

		

		

		
		<li><a href="http://www.aamas2015.com/en/AAMAS_2015_USB/aamas/p1801.pdf"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-log-out"> Download PDF</a></li>
		

	</ul>

	
	<pre id="aamas2015-abstract" class="pre pre-scrollable collapse">The environment, as a space shared between agents, is a key component of multiagent systems (MAS). Depending on systems, this space may integrate physical, communication or social dimensions. Each of them has its own process and rules to support agents’ interaction. For instance, in the physical dimension, the rules may be based on the agents’ location. The agents’ interaction is then contextualized and the environment allows a multiagent control since it performs the interactions according to the state and rules of the MAS. The dimensions of the environment are generally connected either in an application dependent adhoc way outside of the agents or within each agent. In order to ensure a multiagent control, the relations between dimensions must be explicit outside of the agents. Using these relations between the environment dimensions, the interaction becomes also multi-dimensional. In this paper we propose to formalize rules and mechanisms to make this connection outside of the agents and in a generic way.</pre>
	

	<pre id="aamas2015-bibtex" class="pre pre-scrollable collapse">@inproceedings{aamas2015,
  address = {Istanbul, Turkey},
  booktitle = {Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS15)},
  editor = {Bordini, Rafael and Elkind, Edith},
  keywords = {Agent-based simulation::Complex systems; Agent- based simulation::Simulation techniques, tools and environments},
  language = {english},
  month = may,
  year = {2015},
  title = {A multidimensional environment implementation for enhancing agent interaction},
  author = {Galland, St{\'e}phane and Balbo, Flavien and Gaud, Nicolas and Rodriguez, Sebastian and Picard, Gauthier and Boissier, Olivier},
  pdf = {{http://www.aamas2015.com/en/AAMAS_2015_USB/aamas/p1801.pdf}}
}
</pre>

</div>
</li></ol></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accepted paper on SARL at JFSMA 2014]]></title>
    <link href="/news/2014/06/27/accepted-paper-on-sarl-at-jfsma-2014.html"/>
    <updated>2014-06-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>/news/2014/06/27/accepted-paper-on-sarl-at-jfsma-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An article presenting an environment model in SARL has been accepted at the 2014 JFSMA <a href="http://jfsma14.lcis.fr/">Journées Francophones sur les Systèmes Multi-Agents</a>, 8-10 Octobre 2014 / Loriol-sur-Drôme, France.</p>

<p><strong>Paper description</strong>
<strong>Contextualiser l&#39;interaction entre agents en combinant dimensions sociale et physique au sein de l&#39;environnement</strong></p>

<p><strong>Abstract:</strong>
L&#39;environnement, en tant qu&#39;espace partagé entre agents, est un élément essentiel des systèmes multiagents. Selon les systèmes, cet espace intègre des dimensions différentes comme une dimension physique support à l&#39;ancrage spatial et à l&#39;activité des agents sur cette dimension, ou une dimension sociale support aux communications entre agents. Ces dimensions sont souvent traitées de manière indépendante et ne sont reliées qu&#39;au sein de l&#39;agent qui constitue alors le lieu de jonction et de combinaison des informations véhiculées dans ces différentes dimensions. Il s&#39;avère cependant que la combinaison entre ces dimensions est à considérer également en dehors des agents, pour pouvoir par exemple, situer des communications. Dans cet article, nous proposons un modèle unifié supportant la combinaison des dimensions physiques et sociales pour la mise en oeuvre d&#39;interactions contextualisées entre agents. Ce modèle est développé avec le langage multiagent SARL. Nous illustrons cette proposition par une application de simulation de trafic routier dans la ville de Belfort.</p>

<p><strong>Citing Details</strong></p>

<p><ol class="bibliography"><li><span id="jfsma2014">Galland, S., Gaud, N., Rodriguez, S., Balbo, F., Picard, G., &amp; Boissier, O. (2014). Contextualiser l’interaction entre agents en combinant dimensions sociale et physique au sein de l’environnement. In R. Courdier &amp; J.-P. Jamont (Eds.), <i>Les 22èmes Journées Francophones sur les Systèmes Multi-Agents</i> (pp. 65–74). Loriol-sur-Drôme, France: Cépaduès Éditions.</span>

<div id="jfsma2014-materials">
	<ul class="nav nav-pills">
		
		<li> <a data-toggle="collapse" href="#jfsma2014-abstract"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-eye-open"></span> Abstract</a></li>
		

		<li><a data-toggle="collapse" href="#jfsma2014-bibtex"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-bullhorn"></span> BibTeX</a></li>

		

		

		
		<li><a href="http://www.multiagent.fr/extensions/ICAPManager/pdf/GallandGaudRodriguezBalboPicardBoissier2014.pdf"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-log-out"> Download PDF</a></li>
		

	</ul>

	
	<pre id="jfsma2014-abstract" class="pre pre-scrollable collapse">L’environnement, en tant qu’espace partagé entre agents, est un élément essentiel des systèmes multiagents. Selon les systèmes, cet espace intègre des dimensions différentes comme une dimension physique support à l’ancrage spatial et à l’activité des agents sur cette dimension, ou une dimension sociale support aux communications entre agents. Ces dimensions sont souvent traitées de manière indépendante et ne sont reliées qu’au sein de l’agent qui constitue alors le lieu de jonction et de combinaison des informations véhiculées dans ces différentes dimensions. Il s’avère cependant que la combinaison entre ces dimensions est à considérer également en dehors des agents, pour pouvoir par exemple, situer des communications. Dans cet article, nous proposons un modèle unifié supportant la combinaison des dimensions physiques et sociales pour la mise en \oeuvre d’interactions contextualisées entre agents. Ce modèle est développé avec le langage multiagent SARL. Nous illustrons cette proposition par une application de simulation de trafic routier dans la ville de Belfort.</pre>
	

	<pre id="jfsma2014-bibtex" class="pre pre-scrollable collapse">@inproceedings{jfsma2014,
  author = {Galland, St\'ephane and Gaud, Nicolas and Rodriguez, Sebastian and Balbo, Flavien and Picard, Gauthier and Boissier, Olivier},
  keywords = {Environnement support \`a l'interaction, Environnement physique, Environnement Social, Langage de programmation, Trafic routier},
  title = {Contextualiser l'interaction entre agents en combinant dimensions sociale et physique au sein de l'environnement},
  booktitle = {Les 22\`emes Journ\'ees Francophones sur les Syst\`emes Multi-Agents},
  year = {2014},
  publisher = {C\'epadu\`es \'Editions},
  pages = {65--74},
  isbn = {978-2-36493-154-1},
  editor = {Courdier, R\'emy and Jamont, Jean-Paul},
  address = {Loriol-sur-Dr\^ome, France},
  note = {Best Paper Award},
  pdf = {{http://www.multiagent.fr/extensions/ICAPManager/pdf/GallandGaudRodriguezBalboPicardBoissier2014.pdf}}
}
</pre>

</div>
</li></ol></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
